The rules keep changing.
I've been rehearsing every possible outcome.
Once this thought arises, there is no more room for right or wrong.
I am resolved to sever this flood
so that my soul can break free from mediocrity,
from loneliness and distinction.
One more step and you'll fall into madness.
Don't fall down.
I look towards the top.
Chase !
Refined to perfection.
Never retreat, no matter the danger.
I dare to defy the heavens !
Always overcome the obstacles,
ignite the seas with blood,
bloom through trials and tribulations.
Even the sharpest thorns
will be reduced into ashes.
What is there to fear ?
Renegade Immortal\NSubtitles by Bonobosubs\Nhttps://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
The Thunder Celestial Realm is about to open.
This time,
I must enter the Thunder Pool
to refine enough origin energy.
This is...
pressure ?
Did something happen to the Thunder Pool ?
A Silver-horned Thunder Beast ?
An Illusory Yin puppet ?
Maybe...
He's also a Thunder Celestial Messenger.
But he's only Ascendant ?
How can he be unafraid of the Thunder Pool ?
With just a single glance,
Shengong Hu\NThunder Celestial Messenger\NIllusory Yin\N(Originally Corporeal Yang)
my body and soul were damaged
and my Dao Heart was afraid.
My cultivation even fell to Illusory Yin !
Inside the Heaven Defying Bead,
I had the immense opportunity of seeing the third step.
I only caught a glimpse
yet have already gained such fortune.
If I can fully open the Heaven Defying Door one day...
I can't even imagine...
The gaze that nearly shattered my soul
must be the legendary Dao Sight.
If I could follow him,
this would be the greatest opportunity of my life !
I pay respects to Senior.
What is it ?
Senior,
Junior's name is Shengong Hu,
I'm a member of the Shengong Family of the Southern Domain of Allheaven.
I'm also a rank 2 Thunder Celestial Messenger
and I used to be Corporeal Yang.
I beg Senior
to allow me to pledge myself to you.
Pledge ?
Junior
knows his cultivation is still shallow.
He was frightened by the pressure of my comprehension,
I am not qualified to rely on Senior.
that's why he's saying all this...
But...
There are many cultivation families that rely on their younger generations.
But I'm afraid that
I can't perform it again.
If Senior has any requests,
This Shengong Hu has already reached Corporeal Yang.
I'll do my best to fulfill them !
The heavens can bear witness
to Junior's sincerity !
If he sees through my bluff one day,
it could be dangerous.
I only ask that Senior
offers a few words of guidance when I am about to breakthrough.
I refuse.
Senior,
Junior is willing to offer his Dao Soul
along with his Dao Heart as proof.
I beg Senior,
to allow me to pledge myself for a thousand years !
He's even offering his Dao Soul !?
With his Dao Soul in hand,
I don't need to fear him turning on me.
This guy is pretty decisive.
You won't regret this ?
Junior will never regret it !
Why did you come here ?
The Thunder Celestial Realm is about to open.
Junior plans to cultivate here
to absorb origin energy.
I'm not from Allheaven.
I don't know when the Thunder Celestial Realm will open.
In about 30 years.
By then, one can enter with a Thunder Cauldron.
30 years ?
The Rain Celestial Realm back then
laid the foundation for my campaign across the star systems.
No matter what happens,
I must visit the Thunder Celestial Realm.
What are the cultivation restrictions
for entering the Thunder Celestial Realm ?
Senior,
Peak Late stage Ascendant and below
are allowed to enter.
But the Thunder Celestial Temple has a secret method
to allow second step cultivators
to also enter.
However, while inside,
they mustn't use spells above Early stage Nirvana Scryer
or else
it will trigger the collapse of the fragment.
In that case...
70 steps !?
80 steps !
95 steps...
100 steps !
He walked 100 steps forward
as if it were nothing.
Senior is indeed an expert who has concealed his cultivation !
The gamble I made
was correct !
10 steps...
For now,
my limit is 10 steps.
If I were at my peak cultivation,
50 steps wouldn't have been a problem.
When fighting Thunder Daoist,
I used the Heavenly Chop too many times
and nearly exhausted my origin energy.
For first step cultivators,
replenishing origin energy is incredibly difficult.
Fortunately, with my Thunder Origin Soul,
I can use the Thunder Origin Spell to convert this thunder energy into origin energy.
I must recover as quickly as possible !
At the 100-steps mark,
he's still absorbing such a massive amount of thunder energy.
If it were me,
my Origin Soul would have been severely damaged.
Senior's cultivation
is unfathomable !
2 years later
At the edge of the pool,
the thunder is sparse and impure.
Only at the middle of it
will I be able to refine purer origin energy.
To recover quickly,
I must go deeper !
He moved !
Senior is finally going to move again !
Those 2 years of waiting
were just for this moment !
If I can catch even a glimpse of Senior's spells,
it will be a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity !
The thunder energy here
is astonishing.
10 steps...
Senior moved again
but how could he only walk 10 steps ?
Could that terrifying aura from before
have been a coincidence ?
Then my pledge
would become the greatest joke of all time !
Even with all my strength, I still can't reach the center.
My Origin Soul shares the same origin as thunder,
there must be a way to advance.
Same origin, yet repelled ?
Could it be...
that the key is not strength
but the Dao ?
All phenomena in the universe
originate from within oneself.
If it's not a matter of strength,
it's a matter of alignment with the Dao.
Only when the Dao is aligned can origin energy be absorbed.
He...
stepped on a thunderbolt ?
The thunder became his steps
as if it was welcoming him !
This is the true pinnacle of the Dao of Thunder !
I waited 2 years
to see
what kind of spell my Lord would use !
A glimpse at the third step...
A comprehension of the Dao...
Although it wasn't offensive power,
it's far more precious
than countless spells.
This place
sure is lively.
Zhan Konglie !
Zhan Konglie\NThunder Celestial Messenger\NCorporeal Yang
A Late stage Ascendant
can actually enter the inner Thunder Pool ?
He must possess some extraordinary artifact to resist the thunder !
This place is not for you.
Scram !
I wondered who it was,
so it's Shengong Hu.
My eyesight is poor,
I didn't recognize you at first.
Your cultivation
has dropped quite a bit.
It's none of your business !
This young friend looks unfamiliar.
To be able to sit safely in the inner pool,
you must have a rare artifact.
Why don't you take it out
and let me have a look ?
Master,
we're doomed !
A disaster has fallen from the sky !
This guy means trouble.
If we get exposed,
everything will be over...
Corporeal Yang cultivation ?
This man believes I possess a powerful artifact...
He will not let this go easily.
In order to show me his loyalty,
Shengong Hu will surely defend me.
Earlier, due to the disparity in cultivation,
I had to go along with him.
But today, with my Lord by my side,
why should I fear him ?
You have 3 breaths
to scram
or you'll die !
You're willing to fight to the death with me
for the sake of an Ascendant with an artifact ?
Shengong Hu,
what kind of game are you playing ?
Zhan Konglie,
prepare to die !
I'll see this through to the end !
Let me see
what you're really up to !
They're fighting !
Since Shen Gong Hu's cultivation dropped,
he definitely won't hold on.
If Shengong Hu loses,
I will fall into Zhan Konglie's hands.
If I retreat now,
Shengong Hu will be suspicious of me
and it will also put me in danger.
Shengong Hu,
I will not help you in this duel.
Consider it a test of your pledge to me.
If you lose,
I will return your Dao Soul.
Rest assured my Lord,
Shengong Hu will not disgrace your name !
Lord ?
To monopolize the artifact,
you've staged such a clumsy act with this kid
just to try to scare me, Zhan Konglie ?
What a joke !
Such a powerful thunder-summoning spell !
He used origin energy to summon heavenly thunder.
It's like the Furnace Becomes the World spell.
His mastery of the spell
seems incomplete.
Something isn't harmonious in this spell.
I've found the way out
of this situation.
Go !
I've always hated you.
After testing you today,
you do have some skill after all !
Shengong Hu,
your origin spell contained the power of thunder
but not the soul of thunder.
Although your Dao Heart fused with it,
it isn’t enough. Your faith lacks the power of thunder.
My Lord is right,
this is Junior's bottleneck.
I beg my Lord for guidance !
Merging the Dao Heart with thunder...
who doesn't know that ?
But the cultivation path is uncertain,
no one truly knows the direction.
Anyone can spout that kind of vague, abstract nonsense.
Still putting on an act ?
Let's see how this ends for you !
Do you understand now ?
Discard the superficial
and return to the origin...
Only by breaking the situation this way,
can I subdue the enemy without fighting
and scare off Zhan Konglie.
He pointed him directly to the origin of the Dao ?
Shengong Hu's Dao Heart cultivation
has actually advanced in an instant !?
This man is definitely not Ascendant.
His cultivation is unfathomable.
My Lord's guidance
is like a second chance at life !
Junior
understands now !
Zhan Konglie,
let's fight again !
Junior Zhan Konglie
didn't see clearly
and offended Senior's cultivation.
I beg Senior for forgiveness.
Congratulations, Brother Shengong,
you have found a wise master.
This is
a tremendous fortune.
I'm convinced of it.
I have gotten a summon book from the Thunder Celestial Temple.
From now on, we shall serve as fellow messengers.
Farewell !
My Lord,
I apologize for disturbing you.
What's a summon book ?
My Lord,
summon books are communication tools from the Thunder Celestial Temple.
Every candidate for becoming a messenger
gets one.
3 months before each opening of the Thunder Celestial Realm,
the candidates will compete with each other for the position
and fill the spots of the missing messengers.
With Zhan Konglie's cultivation,
he should be able to secure a spot
if nothing goes wrong.
Shengong Hu being here
may attract more unnecessary trouble.
I wish to go into seclusion for a while
to comprehend an important spell.
You may leave now.
This is a transmission jade slip.
Should my Lord need anything,
I will come immediately.
This jade slip
contains a detailed map of the Southern Domain of Allheaven.
It may serve as a guide
for my Lord.
You can go.
8 years later
After 10 years of absorption,
my Origin Soul is full.
I have no more room for origin energy.
This is a cultivation bottleneck.
To go any further,
I must breakthrough to the second step.
Now that the 5 elements are complete,
the bead has this Yin-Yang appearance.
What does it mean ?
Heaven Defying Bead,
what do you need
for your next step ?
Thankfully,
Wan'er and the others' souls are safe.
They seem even more stable than before.
The Thunder Celestial Realm will open in 20 years.
The top priority
is to have a breakthrough in my cultivation.
In the Southern domain of Allheaven,
there are many abandoned planets
with mortal settlements.
They're perfect for concealing my tracks
and focusing on cultivation.
I need to settle somewhere soon.
It's about time
I get my own cultivation planet in the Allheaven Star System.
Once their Dao Soul was controlled by someone else, although it wasn’t the same as death, their Dao Heart could be affected. The consequences had much longer-lasting significance.\NGiving his Dao Soul showed Shengong Hu’s sincerity!\N\N---\N\NLater in the episode, Wang Lin has a breakthrough in his understanding of thunder. It isn't explained in the donghua but in the novel it's said that Wang Lin had "vaguely seen" the law of thunder.\NUnderstanding laws is a fundamental part of being a second step cultivator.
Ask
Qi Condensation
the perilous path filled with countless blades.
Foundation Establishment
Can the mundane world be shattered
Core Formation
Nascent Soul
by a child's steadfast heart ?
If the laws of this world
Soul Formation
Soul Transformation
stand in the way,
I'll defy the universe to tread the heavens
Ascendant
and ask this question to the sky.
My heart's deepest wish
is to not kneel before these mountains and rivers.
Don't accept your doomed fate,
karma can be changed.
Unwilling to let go,
my obsessions propel me forward.
Don't be afraid.
Thunder rumbles as I dare to tread through the reincarnation cycle.
Accept your fate and stay mortal or defy it to become immortal.
Hold fast to this resolve and break through the obstacles.
I'll fight all those who dare to stand in my way.
Let the winds of war heed my command.
I sign this question with my heart.
What is the Dao ?
Defying the flow of heaven and earth,
the heart I cultivate stays true.
I contemplate the wisdom of heaven and earth.
I shall choose my path between karma and fate.
My unshakable Dao Heart
aspires to ascend.
Defying,
this is what my journey to treading the heavens relies on.
Accept your fate and stay mortal or defy it to become immortal.
Hold fast to this resolve and break through the obstacles.
I'll fight all those who dare to stand in my way.
Let the winds of war heed my command.
I sign this question with my heart.
What is the Dao ?
Defying the flow of heaven and earth,
the heart I cultivate stays true.
I contemplate the wisdom of heaven and earth.
I shall choose my path between karma and fate.
My unshakable Dao Heart
aspires to ascend.
Defying,
this is what my journey to treading the heavens relies on.